<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>aws on Jack Collins</title>
    <link>/tags/aws/</link>
    <description>Recent content in aws on Jack Collins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 01:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/aws/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>AWS curl to 169.254.169.254 failing, 401 Unauthorized</title>
      <link>/articles/ec2_imdsv2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/ec2_imdsv2/</guid>
      <description>Scenario Resolution   Scenario As part of my simple bash script to automate AMI creation in EC2, using AWS CLI, a call is made to the &amp;lsquo;special IP address&amp;rsquo; 169.254.169.254 to retrieve the Instance ID for the current EC2 server.
This Instance ID is required in the create-image command I am using, as below, but you may have your own scenarios for using metadata provided by 169.254.169.254.
aws ec2 create-image --instance-id $(curl -s http://169.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AWS Lambda to automate AMI &amp; Snapshots deletion</title>
      <link>/articles/lambda_delete_snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:34:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/lambda_delete_snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Scenario Steps  Create IAM Policy Create IAM Role Create Lambda Function Add Cloudwatch Trigger     Scenario Amazon Machine Images are a great way to back up your AWS EC2 instances, for example before patching.
However, there is no easy way to delete the Images afterwards. Each AMI has underlying Elastic Block Store (EBS) Snapshots attached to it, often many, which to delete require you to deregister the AMI and then find each Snapshot to then remove, via the AWS GUI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Workspaces on RHEL based distros</title>
      <link>/articles/rhel_workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 20:06:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/rhel_workspaces/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Workspaces is a brilliant offering by AWS to allow users access to Windows 10 (or Amazon Linux) based Virtual Machines in the cloud, from anywhere in the world. Unlike EC2, it much more easily scales up for companies to allow remote and cloud based, Active-Directory integrated fleets of VMs for employees. However we can also use it on an individual scale to give access to a true Windows 10 box (not Windows server 2019) from anywhere in the World, without the need for using local CPU, RAM and disk resources for the VM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
