<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jack Collins</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Jack Collins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Useful Pentesting Links</title>
      <link>/articles/pentestinglinks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jul 2023 09:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/pentestinglinks/</guid>
      <description>Last updated : 25/07/2023
A list of useful URLs, for all steps and aspects of a Penetration Test.
This list will be updated as I discover more resources.
If you spot incorrect or broken URLs, or have ideas for additional resources I can add below, feel free to email jackcollins1434@yahoo.com. Thank you.
  Search Engines Reverse Image Searching EXIF Data Location Information Email Address Discovery Password OSINT Usernames &amp;amp; Accounts Specific People Search Phone Numbers   Search Engines Every good OSINT / Reconnaissance has to start somewhere.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using AWS Lambda to automate AMI &amp; Snapshots deletion</title>
      <link>/articles/lambda_delete_snapshots/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Jul 2023 11:34:11 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/lambda_delete_snapshots/</guid>
      <description>Scenario Steps  Create IAM Policy Create IAM Role Create Lambda Function Add Cloudwatch Trigger     Scenario Amazon Machine Images are a great way to back up your AWS EC2 instances, for example before patching.
However, there is no easy way to delete the Images afterwards. Each AMI has underlying Elastic Block Store (EBS) Snapshots attached to it, often many, which to delete require you to deregister the AMI and then find each Snapshot to then remove, via the AWS GUI.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Bastion / Jumpbox Configuration</title>
      <link>/articles/ansible_bastion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 12:29:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/ansible_bastion/</guid>
      <description>Often we&amp;rsquo;ll want to use Ansible to manage many servers, but some of those servers may not sit on the same area of the network. They might be in a Dematerialized Zone (DMZ) and only be accessible via a Bastion / Jumpbox server.
We can configure the Ansible Server to recognise Jumpbox configuration, so that it runs Ansible Playbooks on the DMZ Server, as though it were directly available;
Configuration  Firstly, make sure SSH keys are set up correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible asynchronous actions and polling</title>
      <link>/articles/ansible_async_poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 16:41:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/ansible_async_poll/</guid>
      <description>Ansible will normally run Tasks synchronously, keeping a connection open for the entire time a Task runs.
If we have an especially long running task, for example an apt upgrade/dnf update or a long-running shell script, it may be better to close the connection and then re-establish it every now and then to see if the task has completed.
We might not want connections to stay open for a few reasons;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Python Basics</title>
      <link>/articles/python_cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Apr 2023 06:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/python_cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Strings Advanced Strings Math Variables TypeError (&amp;ldquo;Can only concatenate str&amp;rdquo;) Functions Booleans (LT, GT, EQ, AND, OR, NOT) Conditional Statements (IF, ELIF, ELSE) Lists Tuples Looping (FOR, WHILE) Importing Modules Dictionaries (Key:Value Pairs) Sockets   Strings print(”Hello, world!”) # Double quotes
print(’Hello, world!’) # Single quotes
print(”This string is “+”awesome!”) # Concatenate
print(’\n’) # New line
print(variable_name) # Print a str variable
print(”””This string runs
multiple lines!”””) # Multi-line string</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RPM / Yum - Fatal Error, run database recovery</title>
      <link>/articles/rpm_db_fatalerror/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 12:31:14 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/rpm_db_fatalerror/</guid>
      <description>Scenario When running yum clean all, or yum update, you get an error similar to the following;
error: rpmdb: BDB0113 Thread/process #/# failed: BDB1507 Thread died in Berkley DB library error: db5 error(-30973) from dbenv-&amp;gt;failchk BDB0087 DB_RUNRECOVERY: Fatal error, run database recovery error: cannot open Packages database in /var/lib/rpm CRITICAL:yum.main: Error: rpmdb open failed  Resolution Firstly, try clearing the yum cache and then rebuilding it, via;
sudo rm -rf /var/cache/yum/* sudo yum makecache If that doesn&amp;rsquo;t resolve, kill all yum related processes, delete the cache and all metadata, and rebuild;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Huge Pages in Linux</title>
      <link>/articles/hugepages/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Apr 2023 10:32:22 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/hugepages/</guid>
      <description>What are Huge Pages? Checking the current status of Huge Pages How do I amend Huge Pages? Calculating Huge Pages Miscellaneous notes on Huge Pages   What are Huge Pages? Systems with large amounts of RAM may mean Huge Pages need to be implemented.
Each process has several physical memory segments allocated. To keep them all ‘tidy’ and as near to each other as possible, to keep the system running as fast as possible, the system builds a ‘memory map’, a table, to organise the memory segments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A very basic HackTheBox pentest example</title>
      <link>/articles/htb_example/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 20:15:08 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/htb_example/</guid>
      <description>Reconnaissance Enumeration Gaining Initial Access Privilege Escalation Capture The Flag Conclusion / TL;DR   Reconnaissance The first thing you&amp;rsquo;ll want to do, when starting any penetration test, is scan for open ports. We&amp;rsquo;ll need to recon the server for the OS and running services, so we can start to figure out an attack vector.
We&amp;rsquo;ll start with an Nmap scan, although you could easily use another tool. See my Nmap tool guide for further information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>An overview of Nmap</title>
      <link>/articles/nmap/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 20:14:52 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/nmap/</guid>
      <description>Background Usage Examples Cheatsheet Official Documentation Drawbacks Similar Tools   Background Nmap, or &amp;lsquo;Network Mapper&amp;rsquo;, was originally conceived in 1997 by Gordon Lyon, included as an article in Phrack Magazine along with it&amp;rsquo;s source code. The community at the time were so impressed with it&amp;rsquo;s early capabilities, it was taken up as a collaberative project by the tech community, and remains so right up until today.
Since it&amp;rsquo;s initial creation, Nmap has gone through many big updates, each adding more capabilities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amazon Workspaces on RHEL based distros</title>
      <link>/articles/rhel_workspaces/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Feb 2023 20:06:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/rhel_workspaces/</guid>
      <description>Amazon Workspaces is a brilliant offering by AWS to allow users access to Windows 10 (or Amazon Linux) based Virtual Machines in the cloud, from anywhere in the world. Unlike EC2, it much more easily scales up for companies to allow remote and cloud based, Active-Directory integrated fleets of VMs for employees. However we can also use it on an individual scale to give access to a true Windows 10 box (not Windows server 2019) from anywhere in the World, without the need for using local CPU, RAM and disk resources for the VM.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
