<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>ansible on Jack Collins</title>
    <link>/tags/ansible/</link>
    <description>Recent content in ansible on Jack Collins</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&lt;a href=&#34;https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;CC BY-NC 4.0&lt;/a&gt;</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 20:14:48 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="/tags/ansible/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>An Ansible patching Playbook</title>
      <link>/articles/patching_playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 20:14:48 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/patching_playbook/</guid>
      <description>A couple of years ago I completed the Red Hat Certified Specialist in Ansible Automation course and then took on full onus of patching 600+ Linux servers, where patching was still being done mostly manually.
The solution was of course Ansible, and initially I created a large Playbook on the CLI of our administration server, which worked very well but needed a proper CI/CD solution.
Fast forward a few months and I worked alongside colleagues within Platform Engineering to implement my Playbook in to Git and Visual Studio Code, and then further on I was involved with getting the whole thing covered by Ansible Automation Platform (AAP) and Red Hat Satellite, and triggerable via Azure Devops.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible Bastion / Jumpbox Configuration</title>
      <link>/articles/ansible_bastion/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jun 2023 12:29:42 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/ansible_bastion/</guid>
      <description>Often we&amp;rsquo;ll want to use Ansible to manage many servers, but some of those servers may not sit on the same area of the network. They might be in a Dematerialized Zone (DMZ) and only be accessible via a Bastion / Jumpbox server.
We can configure the Ansible Server to recognise Jumpbox configuration, so that it runs Ansible Playbooks on the DMZ Server, as though it were directly available;
Configuration  Firstly, make sure SSH keys are set up correctly.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ansible asynchronous actions and polling</title>
      <link>/articles/ansible_async_poll/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Apr 2023 16:41:40 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/articles/ansible_async_poll/</guid>
      <description>Ansible will normally run Tasks synchronously, keeping a connection open for the entire time a Task runs.
If we have an especially long running task, for example an apt upgrade/dnf update or a long-running shell script, it may be better to close the connection and then re-establish it every now and then to see if the task has completed.
We might not want connections to stay open for a few reasons;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
